In this clip, I am going to be showing you how to make transitions between your cuts and your videos before putting them on dvd.
I will be using windows movie maker but you can use what ever application you want.
Windows movie making is a trademark of Microsoft, a company of which I have not affiliation with what so ever.
Ok, so we are in windows movie maker again and I have already imported a clip and have split it up and made a couple cuts here, here and here.
So we are going to add some transitions, so what you do is go to story board mode by clicking right here and you will see each of these clips.
You will also see these boxes in between these clips that represent a cut in each of these boxes.
So what you want to do is put a transition here.
You can find transitions by going to the tab and clicking video transitions or you can go to tools and find them right here; you get a bunch of transitions here.
You just pick one, to select, hold it down with the mouse and drop it in the box.
I will just choose some random ones here.
This one looks cool and now we can watch it back and see.
So I will just go back to the time line and move the head right in front of where its will happen and play the footage and you can see.
There is one, moving it forward here, and there is another, and that one is kind of of cool.
Ok, so that is how the transitions work.
Going back to story board here, if you want to delete one just right click and hit delete or you can copy it and move it over to another clip or you can play it.
A bunch of options, so that is how you use video transitions in windows movie maker while editing.